Bernice W. Ames Papers
Bernice W. Ames Papers
1950-1968
Ames, Bernice W.
0.75 linear ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, published material, photographs, clippings of the American poet.
2738241
Biographical History
Bernice W. Ames was an American poet. Her work appeared in Midwest Quarterly, University Review, Yankee, Christian Science Monitor, and in many other publications. She was a member of the Poetry Society of America, and its Bernice W. Ames Award is named for her.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bernice W. Ames Papers consists of correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia, and printed material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type or topic.
Separated Material
A copy of The Various Light: An Anthology of Poetry in Modern English was removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Ames, Bernice W.; Antelope bread.; Women poets.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Bernice Ames, 1967, 1969.
Letter (9/23/55) from Bernice Ames to Mrs. J. J. Henry of Sherman, New York gift of Louise Henry, 2015.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General, A-Z, 6 folders (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Poetry
    - Country of conquest, 1963 (Box 1)
    - If matter is me, 1962 (Box 1)
    - In the center of the world, 1957 (Box 1)
    - The open door, 1950 (Box 1)
    - The rustle of silence, 1954 (Box 1)
    - The rustle of silence, undated (Box 1)
    - She leans from herself, 1965[?] (Box 1)
    - Wind cut, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, individual poems (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - A back door of the poem, Apr 1963 (Box 1)
    - From the sea to the shell, 19 May 1965 (Box 1)
    - Helping your poem to happen, 13 May 1961 (Box 1)
    - The platform of the poem, 12 Sep 1964 (Box 1)
    - Poetry is fun, 1961 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Book reviews, 1958; 1966-1967; for Antelope Bread and In Syllables of Stars (Box 2)
  - Clippings about, 1961; 1963,; 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Nametag, from unidentified event (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Writer's Workshop programs, 1961-1968 (Box 2)
- Published material
  - Book, Antelope Bread by Bernice Ames, published by Alan Swallow, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Poems by Ames, 1954-1968; clippings from magazines, literary journals, etc.; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Stories by Ames, 1957; 1959,; 1963-1968; clippings from magazines, literary journals, etc. (Box 2)